[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What is Python?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
         "A web browser",
        "A database management system",
        "A high-level programming language",
        "A type of snake"
        
      ],
      "answer": "A high-level programming language"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "What is an interpreted language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A language that is executed line by line by an interpreter",
        "A language that only runs on Windows",
        "A language that is compiled into machine code",
        "A low-level language"
      ],
      "answer": "A language that is executed line by line by an interpreter"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "What is a compiled language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        
        "A language that cannot be interpreted",
        "A language used for web design",
        "A language that only works with databases",
        "A language that is compiled directly into machine code"
      ],
      "answer": "A language that is compiled directly into machine code"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "What is a statically typed language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A language that only works with integers",
        "A language used for scripting",
        "A language where variable types are known at compile time",
        "A language that does not require variable declarations"
        
      ],
      "answer": "A language where variable types are known at compile time"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "What is a dynamically typed language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        
        "A language that uses XML for its syntax",
        "A language where variable types are known at runtime",
        "A language used for system programming",
        "A language that requires pre-compilation"
      ],
      "answer": "A language where variable types are known at runtime"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What is weakly typed language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A language that does not allow type casting",
        "A low-level programming language",
        "A language used for AI programming",
        "A language where types are implicit and can change"
      ],
      "answer": "A language where types are implicit and can change"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "What is a strongly typed language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A language used for web development",
        "A language that is platform-specific",
        "A language that enforces strict type compatibility",
        "A language with no type restrictions"
      ],
      "answer": "A language that enforces strict type compatibility"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "What is a .PYC file?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A text file used in Python projects",
        "A database file used by Python",
        "A compiled Python file",
        "A compressed Python file"
        
      ],
      "answer": "A compiled Python file"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "What is PVM?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "Python Version Manager",
        "Python Virtual Machine",
        "Python Video Module",
        "Python Value Mapper"
      ],
      "answer": "Python Virtual Machine"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "What do you mean by high-level language?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A language that is only used for system programming",
        "A language that requires direct memory management",
        "A language with abstraction from machine-level details",
        "A language directly executed by the CPU"
        
      ],
      "answer": "A language with abstraction from machine-level details"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "What is Python known for?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "Its usage only in system-level programming",
        "Its simple syntax and readability",
        "Its complexity and speed",
        "Being a low-level language"
        
      ],
      "answer": "Its simple syntax and readability"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "How does Python internally work?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "It converts Python code directly to machine code",
        "It compiles code to bytecode which runs on the Python Virtual Machine",
        "It translates Python code to Java",
        "It uses C++ to run all Python code"
      ],
      "answer": "It compiles code to bytecode which runs on the Python Virtual Machine"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "What is PEP 8?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A module used for database connectivity",
        "Python's style guide for code formatting",
        "A Python interpreter",
        "A debugging tool in Python"
      ],
      "answer": "Python's style guide for code formatting"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "What is PIP and its use?",
      "optionsCode":[],

      "optionsText": [
        "A Python debugger",
        "A tool for compiling Python programs",
        "A package manager for installing Python libraries",
        "A tool for testing Python code"
      ],
      "answer": "A package manager for installing Python libraries"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "What is bytecode in Python?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "A file format used for data storage in Python",
        "An intermediate code created after Python source code is compiled",
        "The final machine code executed by the CPU",
        "The syntax used in Python"
        
      ],
      "answer": "An intermediate code created after Python source code is compiled"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "What is indentation in Python?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "The way comments are written",
        "A method for formatting strings",
        "The use of whitespace to define code blocks",
        "A tool for debugging code"
      ],
      "answer": "The use of whitespace to define code blocks"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "Does Python rely on indentation?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "Only for function definitions",
        "Yes, for defining code blocks",
        "No, it's optional",
        "Only for comments"
        
      ],
      "answer": "Yes, for defining code blocks"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "What does 'len()' function in Python do?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "Returns the type of an object",
        "Returns the number of items in an object",
        "Calculates the sum of a list",
        "Deletes an object"
      ],
      "answer": "Returns the number of items in an object"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "What is the correct way to create a list in Python?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "my_list = (1, 2, 3)",
        "my_list = {1, 2, 3}",
        "my_list = [1, 2, 3]",
        "my_list = '1, 2, 3'"
      ],
      "answer": "my_list = [1, 2, 3]"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following is a mutable data type in Python?",
      "optionsCode":[],
      "optionsText": [
        "List",
        "String",
        "Integer",
        "Tuple"
        
      ],
      "answer": "List"
    }
  ]
  